=A Puppetry=
= دمية =
=Episode 24=
= الحلقة 24 =
Xiaoxiao.
شياوكسياو.
Song Keyang.
سونغ كيانغ.
I can't go with you anymore.
لا يمكنني الذهاب معك بعد الآن.
However, I'm contented
ومع ذلك ، أنا راضٍ
to be with you.
لأكون معك.
But...
ولكن...
What's it?
ما هذا؟
But,
ولكن،
I want to go to Mai Prefecture
أريد أن أذهب إلى محافظة ماي
with you again
معك مرة أخرى
and eat
ويأكل
the dumplings.
الزلابية.
♪I can still remember how beautiful the thimbleberry bloomed♪
♪ ما زلت أتذكر كم هي جميلة أزهر ثيمبلبيري ♪
♪Time passed by but I can never forget the look in your eyes♪
♪ مر الوقت ولكني لا أستطيع أن أنسى النظرة في عينيك
♪If dreams can prolong our encounter♪
إذا كانت الأحلام يمكن أن تطيل لقائنا ♪
Xiaoxiao.
شياوكسياو.
♪As I see the blooming and passing of the thimbleberry♪
كما أرى تفتح وتوت العليق ♪
♪When will we meet again after this separation?♪
متى نلتقي مرة أخرى بعد هذا الفراق؟
(The inauguration of the Chief of Puppet Clan twenty years ago)
(تنصيب رئيس عشيرة الدمى قبل عشرين عاما)
Here ends the ceremony.
هنا ينتهي الحفل.
The Chief is in power
الرئيس في السلطة
and all people shall submit to Her Grace.
ويخضع جميع الناس لنعمتها.
Kneel.
اركع.
Matriarchy applies to the Puppet Clan.
ينطبق النظام الأم على عشيرة الدمى.
Your mother
والدتك
drained herself off for the Puppet Clan.
استنزفت نفسها من أجل عشيرة الدمى.
And the position of the next chief
ومنصب الرئيس المقبل
will be taken over by you.
سوف تتولى أنت.
I, Moyu, will strive with all my might
أنا ، مويو ، سأسعى بكل ما أوتي من قوة
to protect the Puppet Clan
لحماية عشيرة الدمى
and pass it down to the next generation.
ونقلها إلى الجيل القادم.
The chief of the Puppet Clan
رئيس عشيرة الدمى
has the totem of Iris on them.
لديه الطوطم ايريس عليها.
Once the chief is in danger,
بمجرد أن يصبح الرئيس في خطر ،
the Yuji Puppet can sense her.
يمكن أن تشعرها دمية Yuji.
To protect the sentient beings,
لحماية الكائنات الحية ،
you have to sacrifice your body
عليك أن تضحي بجسدك
to restore peace to the world in return.
لإعادة السلام إلى العالم في المقابل.
I understood.
فهمت.
Push.
يدفع.
Hurry.
عجل.
I can see the baby's head.
أستطيع أن أرى رأس الطفل.
Congratulations, Chief.
مبروك رئيس.
It's a daughter.
إنها ابنة.
(My child,)
(طفلي،)
(you have to shoulder the responsibility of the Puppet Clan)
(عليك أن تتحمل مسؤولية عشيرة الدمى)
(like I did.)
(مثلما فعلت.)
Chief.
رئيس.
Take Yu and leave here now.
خذ يو وغادر هنا الآن.
As the chief of the Puppet Clan,
كرئيس لعشيرة الدمى ،
I'll stay as long as the clan still stands.
سأبقى طالما أن العشيرة لا تزال قائمة.
I must protect the clan
يجب أن أحمي العشيرة
till the last breath of my life.
حتى آخر نفس في حياتي.
As long as you're alive,
ما دمت على قيد الحياة ،
there's still hope.
لا يزال هناك أمل.
Take Yu and leave now.
خذ يو وغادر الآن.
I'll be right behind you.
سأكون خلفك مباشرة.
Leave now.
ارحل الآن.
Chief.
رئيس.
(Chen Residence)
(سكن تشين)
Since we're fated to meet,
منذ أن قدرنا على اللقاء ،
follow me then.
اتبعني بعد ذلك.
I'm the successor of the Puppet Clan.
أنا خليفة عشيرة الدمى.
Many years ago, I was adopted by the troupe leader
قبل عدة سنوات ، تم تبنيي من قبل قائد الفرقة
and was protected by the Chen family.
وكان محميًا من قبل عائلة تشين.
Now that the secret Puppet sorcery was stolen
الآن بعد أن تمت سرقة شعوذة الدمى السرية
and the earth falls apart.
وتنهار الارض.
As the chief,
كرئيس ،
I'll eliminate you today
سأقضي عليك اليوم
to restore peace to the world.
لإعادة السلام إلى العالم.
Do you think you're able
هل تعتقد أنك قادر
to kill me?
لقتلي؟
I fostered the Gu with my blood and flesh.
لقد عززت غو بدمي ولحمي.
Half of my soul
نصف روحي
has attached to the Gu insect.
تعلق على حشرة قو.
There's no one who can conquer the world
لا يوجد أحد يمكنه غزو العالم
except for me.
إلا بالنسبة لي.
How could that be possible?
كيف يمكن أن يكون ذلك ممكنا؟
Master imparted his skills and techniques to you.
لقد نقل المعلم مهاراته وتقنياته إليك.
How could you be so cruel?
كيف يمكنك أن تكون بهذه القسوة؟
♪The dusk outside the window is spreading♪
♪ الغسق خارج النافذة ينتشر
♪The lanterns light up with anticipation♪
الفوانيس تضيء بترقب
♪The sea of lights illuminates the entire theatre♪
♪ بحر الأضواء ينير المسرح بأكمله
♪The galaxy sprawls across the sky♪
المجرة تمتد عبر السماء ♪
♪The moon shows itself♪
القمر يظهر نفسه ♪
♪Gazing at the myriad lives♪
التحديق في حياة لا تعد ولا تحصى ♪
♪The bell chimes and the lady dances♪
يدق الجرس والسيدة ترقص
♪Her movements are mysterious and graceful♪
حركاتها غامضة ورشيقة ♪
♪A woman can solicit cheers and applause too♪
♪ يمكن للمرأة أن تلتمس الهتافات والتصفيق أيضًا ♪
♪Chatters fill the well-lit hall♪
♪ الدردشة تملأ القاعة المضاءة جيدًا
♪Holding a red candle by the stage♪
♪ عقد شمعة حمراء على خشبة المسرح ♪
♪Witnessing the blooming and wilting, oh, the freedom♪
مشاهدة التفتح والذبول يا الحرية
♪The theater welcomes you♪
المسرح يرحب بك ♪